

Tolulope Oyejide

Google Certified Data Analyst

I am an expert data translator who transforms data (small or big) into insightful knowlegde that solves business problems and inspires innovation. I have an excellent understanding and proficiency of platforms for effective data analyses, including SQL, R, Big Query, Tableau, PowerBI, and Spreadsheet. Strong communication, organizational, and analytical skills. I completed the Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, a rigorous, hands-on program that covers the entire scope of the data analysis process.

www.tolulopeoyejide.carrd.co



Lagos, Nigeria

m www.linkedin.com/in/tolulope-oyejide

C

+234 703 611 7831



www.github.com/TolulopeOyejide



tolulopeoyejide.se@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- In this project, I used tidyverse packages in R programming and a spreadsheet to analyze Fitbit users data and made insightful recommendations to Bellabeat Technology Company in order to improve her products quality and marketing activities.
- In this project, I used Power BI Desktop to develop a dynamic and operational dashboard for SmartCare Hospital Limited which helps her track and analyze employee feedback data in order to evaluate employees performances and improve staff retention(lower attrition).
- In this project, I used Power BI Desktop to develop a dashboard that helps Maven Stores analyze her sales data and forecast trends across all of its outlets in order to optimize her operations.
- In this project, I used SQL and Quick DB to develop a relational database for BuyPlux Multiresources Limited which allows them to capture and store all of the key information and data generated by the business.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Website Developer Freelancing 01/2023 to Present

Research, design and implement technical specifications for projects based on user requirements

• Cloud Engineering Intern 06/2021 to 12/2022 The Cloudtician Inc. USA

To improve cloud governance, I communicated cloud concepts to both technical and non-technical audiences across various units within the customers organization.

Translated Information Security Policies and Procedures into language that both business and technical persons could understand

• Website Developer 09/2019 to 06/2021
Servibay Pro Company Lekki, Lagos
Participated in and facilitated communication of technology needs

and requirements to clients and stakeholders INTERESTS Artificial Inteligence Digital Transformation

GENERAL SKILLS

Data Cleaning

Curiosity

Data Validation

Technical Mindset

Data Merging

Analytical Thinking

+ Data Aggregation

- Structured Thinking

+ Data Analysis

- Design Thinking

+ Data Visualization

Communication

Data Storytelling

Data Presentation

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating System:

Windows, Linux

Database/Server:

MySQL, SQL Server

Programming Language:

HTML5, CSS3, C Programming, R Programming, SQL.

Other Software/Tools:

Tableau, PowerBI, Spreadsheet, AWS Services, Prezi, QuickDB, Big Query.

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Business Intelligence Professional Certificate

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate 05/2023

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner 09/2022

EDUCATION

Petroleum Engineering (B.Eng) - 2.1

Federal University of Petroleum Resources Effurun (2011 -2016)